If you have a stem cell, the germarium in women will appear to
form what we call oocytes,
based on a system, and the exact word to use, it means it
cleaves, cleavage.
So you can imagine a cell, it will form two cells, but one has evolved,
stronger.
And we will see that from this small cell, a large...
of cells will appear. And this cell, if you look at it, it
is a collection of cells
and through this cleavage, we see a large cell appear that will be the
oocyte and
surrounding cells called follicular cells and larger cells here called nurse cells.
So we start with the germarium.
A stem cell becomes many cells, I
have tiny surrounding cells called follicular cells,
and then I have large accompanying cells called nurse cells.
One comes from the germline, the other from the somatic line.
Some come from my germline, from my mother, and some come...
from the developmental strength of the nurse cells.
The nurse cells and follicular cells release small molecules.
This is my largest cell which will become the oocyte.
Around here, I have cells that will form the nurse cells.
All around here, I will have cells called follicular cells.
The nurse cells.
And the follicular cells release small
molecules.
And these small molecules will go and
be positioned in the cytoskeleton of
the oocyte.
So they come.
and are positioned in specific
axes in the form of concentration.
In other words, if I place you all over there,
the metabolic concentration will be higher there than
here.
Here, to me.
This will form what we call the top flag.
And what will it do? It will have a concentration like this.
If I have a concentration, it means I have a plus, and therefore I have a minus.
It will do the same in another axis called the apico-caudal axis.
This means that the oocyte, in its development, it polarizes.
It has created axes of force concentration.
to capture this electromagnetic concentration.
So it is oriented within itself.
When you look at a nucleus, a cell,
you see that the cell has two large centers.
A pure cellular center, with the nucleus,
and a structural center,
with what we call centrioles, and...
What we call microtubules.
The cell will cleave, multiply.
There is a participation from the structural center and a participation from the cellular center.
There, it will be the release in the form of my DNA, in the form of
a photocopy.
I can never take the books out of the library.
I can make copies.
And here, there will be a...
Do you remember that...
we had what we call
the equatorial plate
with these small images
these two little things
and then it looked like this
and then the mixture around
well it starts from there
you'll need to keep that in mind
for our work
we'll try to follow
to follow
the polarity
at each step
it will be present
but in a form
different. I take a cell, I
put a nucleus, I have an environment, I
have a compartment
extracellular, intracellular, a nucleus, a membrane, and
a space. We will talk in the field
of development about what we have.
To understand all the embryonic development in a specific process, we’ll talk
about what we call a metabolic field.
What is a metabolic field?
It’s a space within which the cell
evolves.
It’s a structural space.
Let’s recap.
Autocrine communication.
I’m in...
the street and I absolutely need to pee. I
have a device to commit a crime, I pee,
but at that moment, there’s a strong gust of wind. Everything comes back
on my pants.
I feel the warmth, autocrine communication. We
are going to pee together in the bushes,
but the wind is strong again.
Paracrine communication, it all comes on you.
I have peed in the ditch, does that term work for you for a ditch?
I pee in the ditch, and it flows.
You’re playing marbles, hop, and communication, that’s in the circulatory system, the ditch.
So it would be endocrine.
Now what is a communication?
Neurocrine. It’s like paracrine communication, but at a distance. I take
a cell, I make a pupil on myself. I take two cells, I
make a pupil on my neighbor. I take a cell, I go into a ditch and
I touch another one over there.
Endocrine communication. Now I have a cell here, and neuronal cells,
what do they do? They create a large axon.
we have close communications
and long-distance communications
telecrine means at a distance
and then we also have just
tacrine, but I’ll explain that
if I have a cell here
we're going to explain
what the introduction is
of a
metabolic field. He ate sauerkraut twice. I
am here in the corner of the sauerkraut
and I need to release some gas. Someone who enters the room cannot
see it, but immediately knows
where my metabolic field is. There is
a space around me that appears in which there are little
and which are present in a field around me, because
after that it will structure, it will organize, it
will complexify.
Differentiation, changing position, changing form, and changing
structure and function, that is differentiation.
Two functions, two different shapes. The shape is different.
The term biodynamic that needs to be understood, is bio, meaning life, and
dynamic, the dynamism of life in its development.
So that’s important.
In this concept, there’s a Blechmidt who talks about metabolic fields.
And he talks about different metabolic fields.
But to open the introduction and to understand what a metabolic field is,
you used the exact word, you told me you don’t understand the difference between this metabolic field,
and the environment, and well I tell you that’s it, it’s an environment around
but one that will
structure and I will explain that little by little so I am here like this and I am in
a space
around me and as long as I am in this space everything is fine. At some point,
there is a boundary
I touch the boundaries
Two markers appear.
There is an impulse behind that causes a change.
And then I have a boundary that is a bit more troublesome.
It’s a boundary here.
Well, not more troublesome, it’s a boundary on which,
if I go a little further, I provoke a differentiation.
First, I provoke a multiplication,
and then a multiplication with differentiation.
It will depend on the impact I...
have in my spatio-temporal space and the genetic response to the environment.
There are limits on which the system can
multiply, differentiate, and it’s there
where there are traumas, which are shocks, that can provoke deep differentiations
in the system. So at some point
it is necessary to recognize these patterns. And thus we have
references.
We will study to help the body restructure.
Because it has this power within itself,
do you remember, we have this self-regulation.
If I place cells like this,
the environment around them,
through growth systems,
the forces that will come around them,
will provoke at some point
cell division,
cell multiplication.
For there to be differentiation,
there must already be a higher pressure.
in another environment. And so it’s just to explain that there is a difference
between multiplication and multiplication with
differentiation. And that if at some point
the cell receives too strong a constraint, it dies.
And we will see that the body
uses both to develop, to grow, processes,
it will multiply,
where it will.
multiply and differentiate.
And in some cases, it will experience what we call cell death,
which we call cellular apoptosis.
Here, I have a bunch of cells,
and they receive too much constraint,
mechanical compression constraint, for example.
And well, what will remain is just a cellular exudate.